I'm off! I'm off!
Mokku, be careful out there.
I know!
He's really changed. He's
become so dependable.
Let's see... no, no.
The folks in this village
don't eat anything decent.
Honestly... do they really want us
to starve to death? Good grief... Huh?
How mysterious...
The scent of meat!
You bastard!
Trying to hog it all to
yourself, you damn jerk!
I wonder why.
Oh, give me a break. Huh?
Here comes Mokku.
Where do you think he's heading?
Well, well, well, where
are you off to, little Mokku?
Oh, Kenken. I'm going to town for Grandpa
to order some new woodcarving tools.
To town, huh? I wonder why...
Maybe we should tag along with you?
It's all right. I can go
by myself. See you later!
Hmph, he's gotten awfully cocky lately.
Town, huh? Haven't been there in a while.
You thieving cat!
I-I'm a weasel! I wonder why.
This place is amazing.
There's so much stuff here.
No, no. Don't get distracted.
Straight to the tool shop.
Let's see, where's the tool shop...
Watch out! Get out of the way!
Clack-clack, that's so cool.
But pushing me aside
and not even apologizing...
All right!
Hey, you!
What?
Where is First Street?
How should I know? I
always ride in a carriage.
Hey, that was dangerous!
I almost got hit by a bus!
That's because you were
daydreaming, country bumpkin.
What's a country bumpkin?
It means an idiot.
What did you say?
Chikaro?
Let's go!
Who on earth was that guy?
First Street isn't that way!
You're supposed to go
straight to the tool shop!
That's why I'm looking for the way!
And I'm telling you that's the wrong way!
I can go this way too!
Mokku, the city is full of strange folks.
You'll never get anywhere
if you let them bother you!
Come on, hurry up and finish your errand!
I know that. But he is going somewhere.
I'll keep an eye on him for a bit.
Don't worry, it's going to be okay.
Mokku! You can't do that!
Oh, he's eating it. He
looks just like a human.
Madame, please have a seat.
Chikaro is as cute as ever.
He's quite a handful with his mischief.
Chikaro, go play in the garden for a bit.
Yes.
Hey, you!
Hey there, country bumpkin. Still lost?
I followed you here.
You're not human, are you?
I am a chimpanzee, an
ape far superior to humans!
Are apes really superior to humans?
Apes were born into this world
long before humans ever were!
But humans can make all kinds
of things and seem to do anything.
Humans just multiply like rats and
do everything through sheer numbers.
We ape kind prefer living peacefully in
Mother Nature. Who are you, anyway?
You're made of wood, huh?
Yeah. Just a wooden puppet.
Though I want to become a human.
Why would a puppet want to become a human?
Huh? Do you have any idea how
much puppets get made fun of?
Hmm, I-I see.
If you became a real human...
...no, something even greater than
human, everyone would be amazed.
Forget being more than human,
just being human is enough!
You know so much, so
please, teach me about humans.
I really don't like dealing
with troublesome things.
Hey wait!
There's no greater teacher than you!
Please!
Take me as your apprentice...
I'm pretty strict. Are you sure about this?
I'm so glad I came to town!
Thief!
You idiot! Run, quick!
Right away, Boss!
Wait!
Boss!
Wait up!
Hanaguro, wait!
That's enough!
I'm sorry, they got away.
Who are you?
I'm Mokku. Starting today,
I'm Mr. Chikaro's apprentice.
Chikaro's apprentice?
Yes.
Well, how interesting. All right.
If you're Chikaro's apprentice, you're
more than welcome. Come on inside.
I humbly accept.
What on earth are you doing?
This is how you play the piano.
Such wonderful music.
This is the power of amateur music!
This is the primal cry.
The rhythm of our ape clan.
Stop it!
Stop that! Such vulgar music!
You've been a bad boy lately, haven't you?
Isn't it because you took this
strange puppet as an apprentice?
Making me out to be the bad guy...
Acting so refined when
you don't know anything...
Seriously! We were just having fun!
I'm sorry...
You get carried away way too easily.
You'll never rule the world like that.
Go cool your head!
What does "rule the world" mean?
And what good does cooling my head do?
Oh, you guys!
Hey, Hanaguro, Mokku's
got some real skill, doesn't he?
Sure does. Managed to slip
right into a huge mansion.
And when you think
about it, that's thanks to us.
Right, Mokku? You get that, don't you?
Cause we pulled off that theft back
then, you get to live such a nice life.
What did you guys come to town for?
There are lots of humans in town.
Lots of humans means lots of food.
I wonder why.
Then why don't you go
look for food in town?
This is someone else's place.
But isn't this your home, too?
I am Chikaro's apprentice, after all.
"I'm the ape's apprentice!" he says!
You'd better cool off!
I did cool off.
He's crazy about that pretentious ape!
Apes are totally outdated!
Outdated? That's not true!
Yeah, that's right! Prepare yourself!
They can't run as fast as us...
...their senses aren't sharp, and
they don't even blow foul air!
Besides, when we die, we leave our
hides behind. What the hell do they do?
So that makes you guys better?
Naturally. How about you
bring us something to eat?
No way!
Hey, Boss, should we use our usual trick?
No, don't...
Hey, I hear Mokku is weak against fire!
If you don't bring us food...
...this house might just burn down
while you and the ape are asleep!
Getting three meals a day for us
should be easy enough, right, little Mokku?
A-All right. I'll bring it.
Our hideout is behind the flowerbed.
We'll be waiting, Mokku.
Where could Mokku have gone?
Did he get lost, or did
someone take him away?
It was too much for him to go alone...
Yes, I'll go to town, too.
Today we're going to the Countess's party.
Let's get dressed up real nice and go.
Mokku, get the bath ready for Chikaro.
I heard foxes and weasels
run faster than you.
So what? Lower animals are the
ones that have to run and jump around.
They prey on anything weaker than them...
...and have to run for their lives the
moment they see something stronger.
So that's why they're always
running away in such a hurry.
They?
Yeah, some old acquaintances of mine.
Don't waste your time on worthless fools.
We're going to become a species
more advanced than humans.
I just want to be human.
Aim higher.
I don't care about aiming high,
I just want to quit doing this.
You've gotten quite rebellious lately.
It's not that, but are apes
really better than humans?
Are you mocking me?
No, no, of course not...
I'll be right back.
Something's off with that Mokku.
Let's go. Mokku, not bad, huh?
Boss, Mokku brought it.
Oh, Mokku, good job, good job.
Here, it's cake.
Boss, what about drinks?
Oh, right. Hey, there's wine, isn't there?
I'm not sure.
It should be in the cellar. You know
what'll happen if you don't bring it.
All right.
Thank you.
Ah, so that's what you're doing. No good.
Quit whining and bring us more!
Here he comes! Come on!
Mokku! You were working with
those thieves the whole time!
Time to run!
Hey wait!
I won't let you escape.
No, that's not true! Those guys, they—
Quiet, you! Shut your
mouth and come with me!
- There's an explanation for this!
- Save your excuses!
You've got it wrong, I'm
not working with them!
Chikaro! Help!
Chikaro please! Chikaro!
Help me! Come on, listen to me!
You really tricked your way
into this house, didn't you!
Just wait, I'll toss you into the fireplace
along with the junk! Prepare yourself!
That's the thing! They said they'd burn the
whole house down, so I gave them food...
As if I'd fall for such a cheap act!
I'd rather throw it away than
feed petty thieves like them!
Damn it...
Mokku, how are your accommodations?
Chikaro! Let me out, hurry!
Ending up as firewood is
your destiny. Just give up.
Won't you even try to save your apprentice?
I was a fool to trust a wooden puppet.
Now then, I'll head to the party
and tease those noble ladies.
Chikaro! Help me!
Chikaro! Chikaro!
Don't cry, little lady. I'll
scold him soundly later.
Shall we dance?
Up we go...shh!
Hey, wake up already!
Who gave you permission to come here?
Filthy bastard! I won't even
speak to him! You talk to him!
Right! My mother was getting on my case!
She told me if I'm not around, she'll
starve, so I'd better hurry up and go!
Idiot! What are you talking about?!
Next time, you bring the food!
Like hell I'd do that for you!
Don't act so high and
mighty, you ape bastard!
Shall we get him?
Get him!
Stop that at once!
Shut up!
This is terrible!
They've come for revenge!
Damn it...
What is it?
Boss!
Goodbye!
I wonder why.
How dare you humiliate me at the party!
In the end, you're
nothing but a savage ape.
You're better suited as a circus clown.
Damn it, let me out of the shed!
What's your problem? This is awful!
I don't want this! I don't want
to be sold to the circus! Stop it!
Am I going to be burned?
Mokku!
By apprenticing to an ape...
...did you become a bit more like one?
No! I'm going to become human!
Hurry and take off these chains!
Just mimicking the look and
shape of a human is not enough.
Strength is a good example.
Do you understand?
Then what am I supposed to do?
You must not rush.
You need to build yourself up step by step.
What do you mean, step by step?
You must experience many
things and learn about the world.
And once you learn to
tell right from wrong...
...you will be able
to become human.
It will be hard. But you
must never give up, Mokku.
I don't want to be in the circus.
You're good at the piano and acrobatics,
the circus audience will love you.
No, no way!
I'll be burned to ashes before
I ever find a human heart.
This is a fine ape!
Well then, Madame, I'll be taking the ape.
Take him away already.
Looking at such a filthy ape will
upset my sweet little Marianne. Right?
I don't want to be a circus
freak! Mokku, do something!
Mokku...
No, no! Save me, Mokku!
Mokku! Mokku!
Chikaro, you're full of energy, aren't you?
Miss!
Don't treat animals like toys.
Please truly care for them.
Mokku, is that you, Mokku?
Grandpa.
Mokku.
It's all right now. I don't
like seeing that sad face.
Cheer up, Mokku.
Grandpa!
I'm sorry. I'm so useless.
Grandpa made it back,
so there's no need to worry.
Grandpa!
Mokku makes friends with an orphaned chick.
To Mokku, this lonely baby
stork feels just like a little brother.
One day, the chick is shot and wounded...
...but survives thanks to the
tender care of Mokku and his friends.
Yet as the chick grows day by day...
...it is destined to grow up and
journey to its distant homeland.
Look forward to next week's
Kashi no Ki Mokku!